{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Holozoic nutrition is characterized by", "opta": "phagocytosis of solid nutrients and subsequent formation of phagocytic vacuoles", "optb": "pinocytosis of solid nutrients and subsequent formation of phagocytic vacuoles", "optc": "phagocytosis of soluble nutrients and subsequent formation of phagocytic vacuoles", "optd": "photosynthesis", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Organisms with amoeboid cells that move within a network of mucous tracks using a typical gliding motion belong to which phylum of Protozoa?", "opta": "Labyinthomorpha", "optb": "Microspora", "optc": "Apicomplexa", "optd": "Myxozoa", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Saprozoic nutrition is characterized by", "opta": "phagocytosis of solid nutrients and subsequent formation of phagocytic vacuoles", "optb": "pinocytosis of solid nutrients and subsequent formation of phagocytic vacuoles", "optc": "encystment of solid nutrients and subsequent formation of secretory vacuoles", "optd": "pinocytosis of soluble nutrients and subsequent formation of phagocytic vacuoles", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is least likely to have a rigid cell wall?", "opta": "Bacterium", "optb": "Archaean", "optc": "Fungus", "optd": "Protozoan", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The numbers of nuclear divisions involved in a ciliate undergoing binary fission is", "opta": "greater than conjugation", "optb": "lesser than conjugation", "optc": "equal to conjugation", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a function of cysts for Protozoa?", "opta": "Protect against adverse environments", "optb": "Sites for nuclear reorganization and cell division", "optc": "Serve as a means of transfer between hosts in parasitic species", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not true of protozoa?", "opta": "Lack cell wall", "optb": "Produce no sporebearing structures", "optc": "Comprise the microbial population known as phytoplankton", "optd": "Form active feeding forms called trophozoites", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sexual reproduction in the Protozoa occurs most commonly by", "opta": "conjugation", "optb": "gametangial contact", "optc": "binary fission", "optd": "binary fusion", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Organisms with complex life cycles which include a mammalian host and an insect host and involves schizogony as part of the cycle belong to which phylum of Protozoa?", "opta": "Sarcomastigophora", "optb": "Microspora", "optc": "Apicomplexa", "optd": "Myxozoa", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A protozoan is defined as", "opta": "motile prokaryotic unicellular protist", "optb": "motile eukaryotic unicellular protist", "optc": "motile eukaryotic unicellular photosynthetic protist", "optd": "motile eukaryotic multicellular protist", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Organisms which have spore-forming stage in their life cycle and lack special locomotory organelles belong to which phylum of Protozoa?", "opta": "Microspora", "optb": "Myxozoa", "optc": "Ciliophora", "optd": "Apicomplexa", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Members of the Protozoa may motile by all of the following methods except", "opta": "flagella", "optb": "gliding by slime secretion", "optc": "cilia", "optd": "pseudopodia", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most commonly asexual reproduction in the Protozoa is by", "opta": "conjugation", "optb": "gametangial contact", "optc": "binary fission", "optd": "binary fusion", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following describes the function of a phagocytic vacuole?", "opta": "Contain specific enzymes that perform various functions", "optb": "Maintain osmotic balance by continuous water expulsion", "optc": "Structures that accept male gametes during sexual reproduction", "optd": "Sites of food digestion", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following describes the function of a secretory vacuole?", "opta": "Sites of food digestion", "optb": "Maintain osmotic balance by continuous water expulsion", "optc": "Contain specific enzymes that perform various functions", "optd": "Structures that accept male gametes during sexual reproduction", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Organisms are parasitic and have a resistant spore with one to six coiled polar filaments belong to which phylum of Protozoa?", "opta": "Labyinthomorpha", "optb": "Sarcomastigophora", "optc": "Apicomplexa", "optd": "Myxozoa", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is least likely to get in or on a protozoan such as a diplomonad or trichomonad?", "opta": "Flagella", "optb": "More than one nucleus", "optc": "Genes to produce a cyst form", "optd": "Rigid polysaccharide cell wall", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Members of which phylum of Protozoa are being considered as biological control agents for certain insects?", "opta": "Microspora", "optb": "Sarcomastigophora", "optc": "Apicomplexa", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Protozoa are generally not", "opta": "multicellular", "optb": "microscopic", "optc": "lacking cell walls", "optd": "eukaryotic", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Number of motility structures on flagellated cells is", "opta": "greater than ciliated cells", "optb": "lesser than ciliated cells", "optc": "equal to ciliated cells", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Protozoa have several types of vacuoles.The function of a contractile vacuole is to", "opta": "maintain osmotic balance by continuous water expulsion", "optb": "creates sites of food digestion", "optc": "contain specific enzymes that perform various functions", "optd": "have sites for photosynthesis", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}